The Golem : How He Came Into the World
Directed by Paul Wegener Carl Boese
The first chapter .
The learned Rabbi Loew reads in the stars that misfortune threatens the Jews .
I must speak with Rabbi Jehuda - danger threatens our people .
Call all the elders of the community together to pray .
The stars predict disaster .
DECREED : AGAINST THE JEWS ,
We can no longer neglect the popular complaints against the Jews .
They despise the holy Christian ceremonies ; They endanger the lives and property
of their fellow-men ; They practice black magic .
We decree that all Jews shall leave the city and all territory in sight of the city
before the month is ended . - Imperator
Knight Florian , deliver our edict to the Ghetto .
Venus enters the constellation of Libra ! The auspicious hour has come
to summon the dread spirit Astaroth , and compel him to reveal the magic word .
Then we can bring the Golem to life to save our people .
A messenger from the Emperor is here .
Come with me to the High Rabbi Loew , who is like a father to our whole community .
It was I who drew the Emperor 's horoscope . I warned him twice of danger .
Tell him now that i humbly request an audience with him .
The end of the first chapter .
The second chapter .
The hour has come . The stars favor the wizard .
Guard this secret with your life .
Knight Florian brings the Emperor 's answer .
In memory of your services we will grant you an audience .
Come to the festival at the castle , and amuse us again
with your magical arts .
You shame me , but I will soon have a guardian for you .
If we can compel the powers of darkness to reveal the magic word ,
we can bring the Golem to life .
Who will know the magic word ?
NERYO MANTJE The message to give back the dead to the life .
He who possesses the key of Solomon can force Astaroth to reveal the word .
The hour has come !
Astaroth , Astaroth , appear !
Tell me the magic word !
The word , that so terrible word , I have snatched it .
Now I give back the Golem to the life
The end of the second chapter .
The third chapter .
A strange crew .
This is my new servant , Golem .
The Golem 's first appearance on the street .
This is the Rabbi 's new servant . He cannot speak , but he will not harm you .
He will come to you each day , with a list of the articles we need .
I go today to show the Golem to the Emperor . Stay and guard the house .
The Rose Festival
At the time appointed by the Emperor for the arrival of your father ,
I will leave the castle and come to you . I have bribed your warden .
Place a light in your window as a sign that you are waiting for me .
Florian
He is my creature , called Golem . More I may not tell you .
What manner of miracle will you show us today , strange magician ?
I will show you our people 's history , and our patriarchs .
And if you value your lives , let no one speak or laugh .
Moses , the eternal Jew .
Save me , and I will pardon your people .
The end of the third chapter .
The fourth chapter .
We are saved ! The Emperor has withdrawn his decree .
Awake the sleeping brethren with the joyful sound of the Schofa-horn !
Let us rejoice !
If you have brought the dead to life through magic , beware of that life .
When Uranus enters the house of the planets , Astaroth will demand his creature .
Then the lifeless clay will scorn its master turn to destroy him and all it meets .
Your task , Golem , is fulfilled . Be lifeless clay once again ,
lest the powers of darkness take vengeance .
Master , Jehuda waits below with the elders to escort you
to the synagogue for the ceremony of thanks .
After all have left , steal through the gate .
I will be the first to bring the joyful news to Miriam !
I am not ready . Go and I will follow you .
No , I will wait and take you to the synagogue .
In there is a stranger who has brought shame on us . Seize him !
The end of the fourth chapter .
The fifth chapter .
Your house is in flames - the Golem is raging .
The demon has carried Miriam away - destroying everything in his path !
Rabbi , save us , or we shall all perish !
Let us show our gratitude to the great Rabbi Loew .
Rabbi Loew , the people are here to thank you for preserving their safety .
The Rabbi 's house is in ruins and every trace of the stranger is lost .
No other man knows or suspects . I shall be silent forever - will you forgive me ?
The Golem , the Golem .
But where is the Golem ?
The gate has been forced ! The Golem must be there
Give thanks to Jehovah , for today He has thrice shown His love for His people .